ÖMER YEL

Sakarya/Turkey | +90 551 975 04 84 | omervel54@gmail.com | LinkedIn | Github

ABOUT ME

Over 1 year of experience as a Full-Stack Developer. Have a good understanding of complete software development life cycle including Requirement Analysis, Design, Development, Integration, and Maintenance of various client/server web applications. Can effectively work in both independent and collaborative work environments. Excellent communication and interpersonal skills and documentation skills.

WORK EXPERIENCE

FULL-STACK DEVELOPER | FINTECH | 03/2023 - PRESENT

- Development of Bunnynet Api .NET Endpoints
- Development of Insurance Reports Download Automation Tool
- Development of ERP application is in progress
- Used Technologies: ASP.NET Core, Web API, Git, SQL Server, Selenium, FullStackHero Template

FULL-STACK DEVELOPER | UBFSOFT | 02/2022 - 02/2023

- Full-Stack development on various projects.
- Development of <u>spritecss.ubfsoft.com</u> website.
- Development of MeetCe Video Conference Application.
- Development of UbfLicensing Sales & Management Platform.
- Development New Features, Maintenance & Bug Fixes.
- Working with RESTful Services, 3rd party Libraries & Frameworks.
- Used Technologies: ASP.NET Core MVC, JavaScript, CSS, Bootstrap, JQuery, Microsoft SQL Server, Microsoft TFS/Azure DevOps Server

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT INTERN | SABİM |07/2019 - 08/2019

- Development of appointment website for worker who serve medical services.
- Used Technologies: ASP.NET MVC, JavaScript, CSS, Bootstrap, JQuery, Microsoft SQL Server

HARDWARE DEVELOPMENT INTERN | YILKA AUTO TECHNOLOGY | 07/2018 - 08/2018

Researching about computer electronics and its components.

EDUCATION

M. SC. COMPUTER ENGINEERING | SAKARYA UNIVERSITY

• 02/2021 - Present

B. SC. COMPUTER ENGINEERING | SAKARYA UNIVERSITY

09/2016 - 09/2019

B. SC. COMPUTER ENGINEERING | IZMIR INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY

09/2014 - 06/2016

PROJECTS

MEETCE

- MeetCe is a video conference application.
- Development of MeetCe website.
- Front-End & Back-End Development.
- Implementing CRUD operations on MSSQL database.
- Development of user meeting management system.
- Implementing multi-language support.
- Development of file management section.
- Used Technologies: ASP.NET Core MVC, JavaScript, CSS, Bootstrap, JQuery, Microsoft SQL Server, Microsoft TFS/Azure DevOps Server
- Project Link: <u>meetce.com</u>

UBF LICENSING

- Product licensing application.
- Development of user license management system
- Development of product purchase system.
- Front-End & Back-End Development.
- Used Technologies: ASP.NET Core MVC, JavaScript, CSS, Bootstrap, JQuery, Microsoft SQL Server, Microsoft TFS/Azure DevOps Server

CSS SPRITE GENERATOR

- Sprite Generator creates large and concatenated image from selected image file.
- Sprite files make website load faster.
- Front-End & Back-End Development.
- Used Technologies: ASP.NET Core MVC, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, JQuery
- Project Link: <u>spritecss.ubfsoft.com</u>

OTTOMAN ALPHABET OCR

- University graduation project.
- Ottoman Alphabet is deep learning based image to text converting application.
- Project output is mobile application that converts letters from Ottoman alphabet to Turkish alphabet.
- Used Technologies: Python, React-Native, OpenCV, Keras, TensorFlow, NumPy, Python Imaging Library (PIL)
- Project Link: https://github.com/omeryel/Ottoman-Alphabet-OCR

GITHUB PROJECTS

 For my Open-Source projects on github.com. https://github.com/omeryel

SKILLS

- ASP.NET Core MVC
- JavaScript, JQuery
- CSS, Bootstrap
- Microsoft SQL Server
- Microsoft TFS/Azure DevOps Server
- Microsoft Visual Studio
- Object Oriented Programming
- RESTful Services, JSON, API Integration, Networking
- Linux, Bash Scripting
- TCP-IP

COURSES

SIGORTA BILGI VE GOZETIM MERKEZI BOOTCAMP | 04/2022 - 05-2022

• Introduction to Web Security, Digital Forensics and Incident Response

IS BANK CYBER SECURITY BOOTCAMP | 11/2021 - 12/2021

• Introduction to Linux, IT Network, Cryptology, Offensive Security

REFERENCES

Uğur HAMZADAYI CTO, UBFSOFT +90 543 221 59 88

Birol APAYDIN Full-Stack Developer, UBFSOFT +90 530 823 83 18